## JOHANN TAYLOR

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/johann-taylor/ | Portfolio: https://johanntaylor.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com/johannt91

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a pianist and piano pedagogue entering the world of tech as a front-end developer. Leveraging my experience as an educator, I have been able to cultivate the problem solving skills necessary for my success as a developer. I always aim to write quality code as I consider it to be synonymous with crafting an intricate musical composition.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, MySQL, Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars.js, REST APIs, Postman, Git

### **PROJECTS**

### **Tech Blog | GitHub**

Built a basic CMS style blog site with CRUD functionality that uses the MVC architecture.

## WeatherApp | GitHub

- Built a weather app that provides current and future weather forecasts in cities using OpenWeatherMap API
- Built a search engine leveraging Web Speech API to optimize accessibility

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Research assistant University of Toronto, Music Theory Department, Faculty of Music

2022 - Present Toronto, ON

- Collaborate on a database that collects analyses of classical musical pieces to support music theorists (Ruby on Rails, Postgres)
- Provide regular updates to department stakeholder in the form of weekly standups
- Scope problem space in exploratory meetings with music department stakeholder discussing implementation details and trade-offs
- Refactored codebase to make it more readable and idiomatic for future developers

# Freelance Web Developer

2021 - Present Toronto, ON

# University of Toronto, Piano Pedagogy Department, Faculty of Music

- Redesigned and developed the piano pedagogy website using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Hold bi-weekly standups with the department head to ensure that content is polished
- Implemented mobile responsiveness to increase mobile traffic

### Private piano and group class instructor

## University of Toronto Children's Piano Pedagogy Program (part-time)

2017 - Present

- Lead group and private classes with children aged 5 to 11
- Collaborate and coordinate with other instructors to prepare and execute lesson activities
- Communicate weekly updates to parents regarding their children's progress
- Plan and coordinate end-of-semester student recitals using Microsoft Word and Excel
- Adjudicate performance events which involve writing constructive feedback for students

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development - University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies

- 24-week program focusing on technologies related to MERN stack development
- Collaborated and lead small teams for projects

## Master of Music, Piano performance and Pedagogy – University of Toronto

 Specialized in teaching piano to children and coaching advanced amateur adult students through creative exercises in critical thinking and problem solving

## BA in Musical Arts – University of the West Indies, Trinidad and Tobago

Pursued a program that combined music education and piano performance